ABHIJEET SAXENA

(762)014-6989 saxenaabhijeet@outlook.com

Experienced Web Developer with 4 years of experience in writing web applications. Avid learner and technology enthusiast. Motivated team player who is comfortable owning and executing complex projects. Saving companies time and money with innovative ideas and solutions.

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer Engineer

BookMyShow, Bangalore

August 2019 - Present

- Working as a developer in the Front-End team for Live Entertainment vertical.
- Modularized synopsis page which ultimately optimized its performance and also allowed us to feature toggle any component as per our wish. Also Integrated Superstars Offers and currently working on its UI Redesign.
- Developed the core project for 3rd party integration of BookMyShow with PhonePe (BMS PhonePe switch).
- Developing additional UI features for the Unified Seating System app used for creating seat layouts for events.

Senior Developer

Principal Global Services, Pune

July 2016 - August 2019

- Led the Web Development team developing complex responsive UIs in React.js/Angular 5 for new features
- Developed an optimized UI for handling customer requests. Slashed average call time by 70%. Led to savings of 4
 FTE.

PROJECTS

- WEB-V3 (2019-2020) Core project that powers the Live Entertainment flow at BookMyShow. Large scale project capable of handling thousands of requests/second. Uses React, Node, Redux-Saga, Babel, Webpack, etc.
- Flex Staff (2019) Web platform where leaders can publish work that'll be picked by freelancers working remotely. Allowed tapping overlooked freelancers market. Angular 7, Springboot, AWS, PostgreSQL
- **Policy Snapshot** (2018) Single Page Application used by call center representatives to get a consolidated view of policy information. Java REST API, Spring, Angular 5
- Structured Summary (2018) React.js SPA for Medical Reviewers to enter medical details and generate an Intelligent Summary which presents a concise medical summary of Insured to the underwriter enabling faster underwriting. React, Redux, Browser Local storage

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ES6, JQuery, AJAX, Angular, React, Redux, Babel, Webpack, SASS, WebSockets, Local Storage, Jest, Responsive and mobile-first UI and UX
- Node.js, Java, Relational and NoSQL Databases, Working Knowledge of Algorithms and Data Structures
- REST API, Git, JIRA, Bitbucket

EDUCATION

Government College of Engineering, Aurangabad

August 2012 - April 2016

• Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication, CGPA- 8.484

ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Ace Performer of the Year (2018) Overall excellence in deliveries
- freeCodeCamp Full Stack Developer Certificate (2019) Over 1800 hours of coding challenges in Responsive Web Design, Front End Libraries, Javascript Algorithms, and Data Structures, Data Visualization, APIs and Microservices and Information Security and Quality Assurance.
- FreeCodeCamp.org JAMStack Hackathon (2018) Ingredea. An app to upload an image of your favorite dish and get back the list of its Ingredients and more recipes of similar dishes along with YouTube video links to the actual recipe. HTML, SASS, JavaScript, Progressive Web App.

CONTACT